<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Burag Cetinkaya</title>
    <link>https://www.burag.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Burag Cetinkaya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.burag.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning SwiftUI and making a game</title>
      <link>https://www.burag.com/post/learning-swiftui-sumnum-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.burag.com/post/learning-swiftui-sumnum-game/</guid>
      <description>When Apple announced SwiftUI about 2 years ago, I was extremely excited. I had previously used Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s WPF and Silverlight with their declarative layour markup language that resonates very well with the way I think about UIs. In the past few months, I finally had a few weekends that I could dedicate to learning SwiftUI at a high level with a simple project.
As I was looking for a project to tinker with, I remembered a number&amp;rsquo;s game I used to play in middle school when I was back in Istanbul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micro Services for engineering growth</title>
      <link>https://www.burag.com/post/micro-services-engineering-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.burag.com/post/micro-services-engineering-growth/</guid>
      <description>Organizational impact of micro-service architecture Using micro-services in your engineering organization is where the hype has been at for the past few years. As others like Martin Fowler have pointed out , building a micro-services architecture based on the hype is probably a bad idea as a true micro-services architecture comes with a whole set of new challenges that probably is not worth it for a good chunk of use cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversational UIs are coming</title>
      <link>https://www.burag.com/post/conversational-uis-are-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 22:09:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.burag.com/post/conversational-uis-are-coming/</guid>
      <description>Conversational style UIs are gaining more popularity. In an era where people are living and breathing text messages and have an attention span for only nuggets of information, I foresee these conversational apps to become the norm.
I would even argue that as speech and video recognition gets more and more accurate, we will have these conversational apps morph into virtual assistants.
Check out this news app that can take a news piece and break it down and make it a conversation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of bad UX in the physical world</title>
      <link>https://www.burag.com/post/bad-ux-at-ticket-kiosks-in-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.burag.com/post/bad-ux-at-ticket-kiosks-in-italy/</guid>
      <description>UX in Italy: 18 screens to buy a train ticket I was in Cinque Terre region in north eastern Italy for a week last month. It is a UNESCO Heritage Site and I definitely recommend it, especially if you like hiking.
Part of our plan was to take trains to neighboring towns and do one-way hikes. Every time we approached the train station to buy our tickets, we ended up seeing a long line of tourists and locals queued up, waiting in 95F degree weather frustrated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media during a military coup</title>
      <link>https://www.burag.com/post/social-media-and-military-coup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.burag.com/post/social-media-and-military-coup/</guid>
      <description>I’ve never been a very active user of social media in the past 10 years except for sharing the occasional funny puppy and soccer video with friends. As a result, every time I’ve read articles and blog posts about how social media was a catalyst in some sort of change, I was quite skeptical.
I guess you have to live it to see it.
Just a few days ago my parents were visiting Istanbul when a group of generals in the military attempted a coup on the government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managers should not be messengers</title>
      <link>https://www.burag.com/post/managers-not-messengers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.burag.com/post/managers-not-messengers/</guid>
      <description>This is a pet peeve of mine; everytime I see a manager trying to get something done by carrying the message between folks he manages and upper management, it makes me cringe. If you are an engineering manager and find yourself in this situation; change the company or change your company.
You need to ask for things you can manage. What do we mean by &amp;ldquo;manage&amp;rdquo; ? A well defined area in which you have accountability and decision making ability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brushing up on programming</title>
      <link>https://www.burag.com/post/brushing-up-on-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.burag.com/post/brushing-up-on-programming/</guid>
      <description>When was the last time you took a week to brush up on the most basic of algorithms and your understanding of data structures? As we get into the rhythm of using our most beloved frameworks, language features and libraries sometimes we do lose touch with the most basic building blocks of computer science. &amp;lsquo;So what?&amp;rsquo; You may ask. When you are designing and building software that will be used by tens of millions of people, it is important to understand the trade-offs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onwards and Upwards</title>
      <link>https://www.burag.com/post/onwards-upwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.burag.com/post/onwards-upwards/</guid>
      <description>No, it&amp;rsquo;s not an April&amp;rsquo;s fool joke! My last day at EPAM Systems (NYSE: EPAM) was April 1st. I am starting a new position at Meetup.com as the Director of Core and Data Engineering. After spending 10+ years in creating solutions and leading teams in healthcare, I wanted to take on new challenges to broaden my horizons, learn more about a different industry and create solutions that help people in a different way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIMSS 2016</title>
      <link>https://www.burag.com/post/himss-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.burag.com/post/himss-2016/</guid>
      <description>I was at HIMSS with EPAM for the past few days. It’s been fun and exhausting at the same time. Here are some observations:
Population health has turned into a buzzword. Everybody talks about it but very few companies can actually describe how they will move the needle. Big Data is yet another buzzword. Without clear definition, everybody is claiming they do big data. Collaboration tools; from data aggregation to secure messaging across providers have matured quite a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>graphs all around us</title>
      <link>https://www.burag.com/post/graphs-all-around-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.burag.com/post/graphs-all-around-us/</guid>
      <description>Do you ever think about how data in your organization is connected or what is buried in the tables/rows that your app writes to? Graph databases have been around for a while but for the first time they are becoming so accessible to app developers with products like Neo4j.
I have been working with NoSQL databases in the past 2 years but I just started getting into graph databases in the past 6 months and it totally changed my perception of the value of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture of Stackoverflow</title>
      <link>https://www.burag.com/post/stackflow-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.burag.com/post/stackflow-architecture/</guid>
      <description>The Architecture of StackOverflow A couple of months ago, I read a comment on Hacker News about how .NET is a poor technology choice for startups for performance reasons. I disagree wholeheartedly. Not because .NET is always the best choice, but because characterizing a platform/language as a poor choice for performance without the context is non-sensical. Today, for most web based applications, performance ranks lower compared to licensing cost, talent pool, existing frameworks, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic resource allocation in your data center</title>
      <link>https://www.burag.com/post/dynamic-resources-in-enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.burag.com/post/dynamic-resources-in-enterprise/</guid>
      <description>By now all of us architects are very much used to the idea of spinning a new server in the cloud and scaling our solution horizontally as needed. Virtually nonexistent setup times and a good API provided by cloud vendors makes this a possibility. Infrastructure has come a long way in the form of IAAS and PAAS. Also, open source software has been a great enabler of this movement; namely deployment automation technologies and linux distributions that are customized per use case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Tmobile&#39;s activation form</title>
      <link>https://www.burag.com/post/fixing-tmobile-activation-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.burag.com/post/fixing-tmobile-activation-form/</guid>
      <description>I was in the process of porting my home phone number to Google Voice and using Obi to connect to my home phone. For those of you who have not heard of it yet; Google Voice offers free calling within the US and Canada and it has many advantages such as ringing many phone numbers. Obi on the other hand is a nice SIP client that can work with Google Voice and other VoIP providers and connect them to your house phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pomodoro Technique</title>
      <link>https://www.burag.com/post/pomodoro-for-remote-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.burag.com/post/pomodoro-for-remote-workers/</guid>
      <description>I am a big fan of the pomodoro technique when the number of things I have to work on start exceeding 5. The technique boils down to having a strict disciple of working for 25 minutes without any interruptions (yes, email and twitter count!) and then taking a small break immediately after. Creating chunks of works like this works for me since I can keep track of how far I am into finishing an activity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
